Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection Ireland Serials TAM.760
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection Ireland Serials
1946-2003
1973-1988
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM.760
1 Linear Feet in 1 half manuscript box and 2 flat boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Ireland Serials contains 28 titles published in Ireland, the United Kingdom, and the United States between 1946 and 2003 on topics related to the political situation in Ireland in the 20th century. The majority of the serials are about the Irish republican movement and the conflict in Northern Ireland in the 1970s and 1980s.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to Ireland drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Ireland Serials contains 28 titles published in Ireland, the United Kingdom, and the United States between 1946 and 2003 on topics related to the political situation in Ireland in the 20th century. The majority of the serials are about the Irish republican movement and the conflict in Northern Ireland in the 1970s and 1980s. Roughly half of the serials in this collection were published by Irish republican organizations in New York and California, including the Irish Northern Aid Society (NORAID), the James Connolly Association, and the Irish Republican Clubs of the USA and Canada. Other organizations include Irish republican and labor organizations in Ireland, Northern Ireland, and England, including Sinn Fein, Republican Sinn Fein, the Irish Republican Movement, and various Irish worker associations. Topics include Irish American support for Irish republicanism, civil rights of Catholic Irish in Northern Ireland and England, the situation of political prisoners in Northern Ireland, and hunger strike in Northern Ireland in 1980 and 1981.
Northern Ireland -- History -- 1969-1994.; Ireland -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements.; Serials (publications); Ireland -- History -- 20th century.; Irish Americans -- Periodicals.
- American Irish National Political Education Committee: American Irish National Political Education Committee, Stony Point, NY, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Irish Newsletter: American Irish Political Education Committee, Stony Point, NY, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- An Phoblacht Republican News: An Phoblacht Republican News, Dublin, Ireland, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Civil Rights Guardian: Irish Civil Rights Action League, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- D.C. Friends of Ireland: D.C. Friends of Ireland, Washington, DC, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Drithleog: Irish Republican Clubs, USA and Canada, New York, NY, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Eolas / Irish Republican Movement: Irish Republican Movement, Dublin, Ireland, 1978 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 7)
- Felon: Irish-American Action Association, San Francisco, CA, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Harp: Irish-American Labor Coalition, New York, NY, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Home Planet News: Home Planet Publications, New York, NY, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Iris: Sinn Fein, Dublin, Ireland, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Irish Citizen: Irish Solidarity Campaign, London, UK, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Irish Freedom News: National Association for Irish Freedom, New York, NY, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Irish Militant: Irish Militant, London, UK, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Irish Northern Aid Committee Newsletter: Irish Northern Aid Committee, San Francisco, CA, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Irish People: The Irish People, Inc., New York, NY, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Irish Review of Politics, Letters and Art: Workers' Weekly, Dublin, Ireland, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Irish Worker: Irish Worker, London, England, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Newsletter from the James Connolly Association: James Connolly Association, New York, NY, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Rising: The Irish Community Support Committee, San Francisco, CA, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Rosc Catha: Clann Na Heireann, London, UK, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
- Saoirse: Republican Sinn Fein, Dublin, Ireland, 1998-2003 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 8)
- Spirit of Freedom: The Spirit of Freedom, New York, NY, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Starry Plough: Official Republican Movement, Derry, Northern Ireland, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 9)
- Two Nations: Workers Association Bulletin: Workers Association for the Democratic Settlement of the National Conflict in Ireland, Belfast, Northern Ireland, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- United Irishman: Republican Publications, Dublin, Ireland, 1972-1974 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 10)
- Voice of the People: Voice of the People Publications, London, UK, 1978 (Box Shared Tamiment 051, Folder 11)
- Workers' Weekly: Brtish & Irish Communist Organization, Belfast, Northern Ireland, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)